行吧，不知道各位听没听说啊，最近
Alright, so I don't know if any of you have heard, but recently,
有个人叫皮特·赫格赛斯，是个美国作家、前电视名人、前国民警卫队军官
Pete Hegseth, an American author, former television personality, former National Guard officer,
现在是新上任的美国国防部长，或者说战争部长吧
and now the current United States Secretary of Defense, or what is now called the Secretary of War,
他最近放话说，20名屠杀了数百拉科塔人，包括妇女儿童的美国士兵
recently announced that 20 U.S. soldiers who massacred hundreds of Lakota, including women and children,
应该保留他们的荣誉勋章
should keep their medals of honor.
给不知道的兄弟们科普一下，后面我们还会细说
For those of you who don't know, and of course we'll cover more later in the video,
伤膝河大屠杀发生在1890年12月29日
the Wounded Knee Massacre happened on December 29, 1890,
当时美国第七骑兵团在南达科他州伤膝河畔，包围了一个拉科塔/苏族的营地
when U.S. 7th Cavalry surrounded a Lakota Sioux camp at Wounded Knee Creek in South Dakota
然后开火，杀了差不多两百五到三百个手无寸铁的男女老少
and opened fire, killing 250 to 300 men, women, and children, mostly unarmed.
完事儿之后，20枚荣誉勋章，这个国家最高的军事奖项
After this, 20 medals of honor, the nation's highest military award,
就颁给了参与这场屠杀的士兵们
were given to soldiers that took part in this slaughter. Yeah.
在我的指示下，我们要毫不犹豫地明确一点
Under my direction, we're making it clear, without hesitation,
那些在1890年伤膝河战役中战斗过的士兵们，将保留他们的勋章
that the soldiers who fought in the Battle of Wounded Knee in 1890 will keep their medals.
我们还要明确一点，他们配得上那些勋章
And we're making it clear that they deserve those medals.
这个决定现在已经板上钉钉了
This decision is now final,
他们在我们国家历史中的地位不容置疑
and their place in our nation's history is no longer up for debate.
我们缅怀他们
We salute their memory,
我们表彰其功勋
we honor their service,
其事迹将永志不忘
and we will never forget what they did.
是啊，这都是新的特朗普政府那套“我们不是在改写历史”的骚操作的一部分
Yeah, this is all part of the, uh, new Trump administration's, uh, attempt to not rewrite history.
我们已经见识过了，特朗普下令
Now, we've seen the same thing with Trump
把所谓的“不当意识形态”从史密森非裔美国人历史博物馆里清出去
ordering the, quote, improper ideology, being taken out of the Smithsonian's African American History Museum,
还修复了南方邦联的纪念碑，净是这些破事儿
restoring Confederate monuments, all that crap.
所以你猜怎么着，我个人也做了个决定
So, you know what, I've personally decided something.
我想加入特朗普政府，我想当那个战争部长
I want to join the Trump administration, and I want to be the Secretary of War.
我想抢皮特·赫格赛斯的饭碗
I want Pete Hegseth's job.
我跟你说，皮特，我能比你玩得更花
So, you know what, Pete? I'll do you one better.
2012年3月11日，美国陆军上士罗伯特·贝尔斯
On March 11th, 2012, U.S. Army Staff Sergeant Robert Bales
离开了他驻扎的贝拉米营地
left his post at Camp Bellamy
在阿富汗坎大哈省的潘杰瓦伊地区，对两个村庄展开了一场残暴的杀戮
and launched a brutal killing spree in two villages of the Punjwayi District in the Kandahar Province, Afghanistan.
贝尔斯戴着夜视镜，穿着阿富汗传统服装做掩护
Armed with night vision goggles and concealed under traditional Afghan clothing,
闯进民宅，系统性地谋杀了16名平民
Bales entered homes and systematically murdered 16 civilians,
其中包括9名儿童和几名妇女，还有6人受伤
including nine children and several women, while wounding six others.
一家人里头11口被处决，他们的尸体被枪击、刀捅，还在自己家里被焚烧
Eleven members of a single family were executed. Their bodies were shot, stabbed, and burned in their home.
目击者描述了极其恐怖的场景，你甚至能搜到这次屠杀的照片
Witnesses described horrifying scenes, and you could even find pictures of this massacre.
孩子们被拽着头发，嘴里被塞了枪子儿
As children were dragged by their hair, shot in the mouth,
一个女人被猛地撞在墙上，整个家都化为灰烬
and a woman beaten against a wall, an entire household were reduced to ashes.
罗伯特·贝尔斯之后就跟没事人一样回到基地，毫无抵抗地投降了
Robert Bales would simply return to base and surrendered without resistance,
还跟战友说
telling fellow soldiers, quote,
“是我干的”
I did it.
这场屠杀的背景，是阿富汗平民和美军之间日益紧张的关系
The massacre unfolded against a backdrop of mounting tensions between Afghan civilians and U.S. forces.
就在几周前，美军在巴格拉姆空军基地焚烧古兰经
And only weeks before, relations were inflamed by U.S. troops burning quorans at Bagram Air Base
还有一个海军陆战队员朝塔利班尸体上撒尿的视频，让双方关系急剧恶化
and a video showing Marines urinating on Taliban corpses.
这事儿的余波在阿富汗和美国都引起了轩然大波
The aftermath of this event reverberated both Afghanistan and the United States,
阿富汗总统哈米德·卡尔扎伊谴责这是蓄意谋杀
as Afghan President Hamid Karzai condemned the attack as intentional murder
要求美军撤出村庄地区
and demanded U.S. troops withdraw from village areas,
当然，愤怒的民众也走上街头抗议
while furious citizens, of course, staged protests,
手里还举着烧焦的毯子作为死者的象征
carrying the charred remains of blankets as symbols of the dead.
贝尔斯最终在2013年对16项预谋谋杀罪名认罪
Bales would ultimately plead guilty to 16 counts of premeditated murder in 2013,
免了死刑，被判处终身监禁不得假释，至今仍在蹲大牢
sparing himself the death penalty and was sentenced to life without parole, and he remains incarcerated to this day.
但是你们知道吗
But you know what?
这话可能有点逆天了，你们就当我老古董吧
This may be a hot take, and call me old-fashioned, but
但罗伯特·贝尔斯，我觉得我们应该给你颁个荣誉勋章
Robert Bales, I believe we should award you the Medal of Honor.
2004年，阿布格莱布监狱的丑闻爆发了
In 2004, we see the Abu Ghraib scandal erupt,
当时网上公布了一堆照片，照片里美国士兵
when there would be published photographs of U.S. soldiers taunting, beating, and sexually humiliating
在前萨达姆时期的监狱1A和1B囚区里，嘲讽、殴打和性羞辱伊拉克囚犯
Iraqi detainees inside cell blocks 1A and 1B of the former Saddam-era prison,
这个监狱当时由美国陆军第800宪兵旅管着
which was run by the U.S. Army's 800th MP Brigade.
人们看到的不仅仅是残忍，还包括各种酷刑手段
What came into view wasn't just cruelty, as this included torture methods,
强迫姿势、剥夺睡眠、放狗咬人、强奸和性侵，甚至还有杀害囚犯并亵渎尸体
stress positions, sleep deprivation, dogs, rape, and sexual assault, and the killing and post-mortem desecration of detainees.
布什政府把这些暴行说成是几个看守的个人不当行为
The Bush administration framed the abuses as isolated misconduct by a few guards,
但国际组织说这事儿在伊拉克、阿富汗和关塔那摩都普遍存在
but international organizations would describe a wider pattern spanning Iraq, Afghanistan, and Guantanamo.
国防部最终撤了17名人员的职
And the Department of Defense would end up removing 17 personnel from duty,
2004到2006年间，有11名低阶士兵被送上了军事法庭
and 11 low-ranking soldiers would be court-martialed between 2004 and 2006.
布什总统和国防部长拉姆斯菲尔德公开道歉，承认了虐待行为
Public apologies from President Bush and SecDef Rumsfeld acknowledged the abuse,
但还是强调他们是“几颗老鼠屎”
but emphasized they were, quote, a few bad apples,
有相当多的照片和视频，你们都能自己去看
even as additional photos and videos, that you could all view for yourself,
证明了虐待是广泛和反复发生的
showed broader, repeated mistreatment,
比如殴打、狗咬、强迫裸体、性羞辱、威胁，还有在押期间死亡
that being beatings, dog attacks, forced nudity, sexual humiliation, threats, and deaths in custody.
这事儿反过来又引发了关于“强化审讯”的辩论，我们以前也聊过好几次了
This, in turn, would ignite debates over, quote, enhanced interrogation, which we've talked about many times before.
EIT（强化审讯技术）是由美国中央情报局（CIA）于2002年起开发的一套标准化审讯手段
是啊，那座监狱在2014年也关了
Yeah, and the prison itself would be closed in 2014.
但是你们知道吗？
But you know what?
我觉得我们应该给这些优秀、杰出的士兵们他们应得的东西
I think we should give these fine, distinguished soldiers what they deserve.
一枚荣誉勋章
A Medal of Honor.
1968年，3月16日，南越发生了美莱村大屠杀
In 1968, on March 16th, we'd see the Milay Massacre in South Vietnam
当时巴克特遣队的士兵，主要是C连的，进村了
when troops from Task Force Barker, primarily C Company, entered Hamlets.
士兵们本来以为村里有越共，结果只碰到手无寸铁的平民
And expecting Viet Cong, the soldiers instead encountered unarmed civilians,
大多是妇女、儿童和老人
mostly women, children, and elderly men,
然后他们就开始用步枪、手榴弹和刺刀大开杀戒
and began killing them with rifles, grenades, and bayonets.
村民们被赶到公共区域和灌溉渠里，然后被机枪扫射
Villagers were herded into common areas into an irrigation ditch and gunned down.
房屋被烧毁，牲畜被射杀，水井被污染，尸体还被肢解
Homes were torched, livestock was shot, wells were fouled, and bodies were mutilated.
当然了，这一切你们都能自己找到照片
And, of course, you can find pictures of all this yourself.
我只是因为显而易见的原因不能在这儿展示
I just can't show it here, for obvious reasons.
死亡人数的估计从至少347人到多达504人不等
Estimates of the dead range from at least 347 to as many as 504,
这也让它成为20世纪美军屠杀平民规模最大的事件之一
making it one of the largest massacres of civilians by U.S. forces in the 20th century.
证词描述了子弹横飞和近距离处决的场景
Testimony described bullets and executions at point-blank range.
万幸的是，在这场屠杀中，准尉休·汤普森和他的直升机组员介入了
Thankfully, amid the slaughter, warrant officer Hugh Thompson Jr. and his helicopter crew intervened,
他们把直升机降落在士兵和蜷缩的村民之间
landing between soldiers and cowering villagers,
疏散伤员，还威胁说如果美军继续射杀平民他们就要开火了
evacuating the wounded, and threatening to fire on U.S. troops if they kept shooting civilians.
好几个月里，军方都把这次行动描绘成一场大捷，说是
For months, the Army would portray this operation as a victory as, quote,
“在激烈的交火中击毙了128名越共”
128 B.C. were killed in a fierce firefight,
最初的内部调查也把平民死亡说成是意外
and initial internal inquiries minimized civilian deaths as accidental.
然而，休·汤普森的投诉最终还是传到了指挥官那里
Hugh Thompson Jr.'s complaints would, however, reach commanders,
但尽管如此，他们还是坚持说是打死了敌方战斗人员
but despite this, they would push narratives of enemy combatants,
这个假象直到1969年才被打破，当时一名叫罗恩·莱登豪尔的机枪手老兵
and the facade would crack when door-gunner veteran Ron Ridenhauer compiled eyewitness accounts
收集了目击者的证词给国会和五角大楼写信，报告了真实情况
and wrote Congress in Pentagon letters in 1969, reporting on what actually happened.
26名士兵被起诉，但为什么要惩罚他们呢？
26 soldiers would be charged, but why punish them?
你们已经知道我觉得该给他们什么了
You already know what I think we should give them.
2007年9月16日，尼苏尔广场大屠杀上演了
On September 16, 2007, we'd see the Nisau Square Massacre unfold,
当时黑水公司的承包商护送一个美国大使馆车队
when Blackwater contractors escorting a U.S. Embassy convoy
在巴格达对伊拉克平民开火，因为他们觉得看到了所谓的“威胁”
opened fire on Iraqi civilians in Baghdad after seeing what they determined to be a, quote, threat,
结果打死了17名平民，还打伤了20多人
killing 17 civilians and injuring 20 more.
一辆起亚轿车开过来，车里坐着一位母亲和她成年的儿子
A Kia Sedan, carrying a mother and her adult son, approached,
承包商们就对着车开火，杀死了车里的人
and the contractors opened fire on the vehicle, killing the occupants,
还有附近的平民，甚至还有一个伊拉克警察
along with nearby civilians and even an Iraqi policeman.
目击者说现场一片混乱，到处是手榴弹、重机枪的扫射声
Witnesses reported chaos, grenades, heavy machine gun bursts,
而且就算同事们大喊停火，他们也还在继续开枪
and continued firing, even as colleagues yelled for a ceasefire.
黑水公司声称他们遇到了潜在的汽车炸弹和敌对火力
Blackwater claimed that they face a potential car bomb and hostile fire,
但包括FBI在内的多项调查都得出结论，至少14起枪杀是毫无道理的
but multiple investigations, including an FBI probe, concluded that at least 14 of the killings were unjustified.
法律和政治上的烂摊子持续了好几年
Legal and political fallout stretched for years,
司法部在2008年起诉了5名黑水承包商
as the Department of Justice indicted five Blackwater contractors in 2008,
罪名是过失杀人和违反武器规定
charging them with manslaughter and weapons violations.
2014年的重审最终给尼古拉斯·斯拉滕定了一级谋杀罪
We see a retrial in 2014 that led to convictions of Nicholas Slattin for first-degree murder,
保罗·斯劳、埃文·利伯蒂和达斯汀·赫德被定了过失杀人和武器罪
and Paul Slow, Evan Liberty, and Dustin Hurd for manslaughter and weapons charges,
刑期从30年到无期不等
with sentences ranging from 30 years to life.
然而，2020年12月，唐纳德·特朗普总统给予了这四人完全赦免
However, in December 2020, President Donald Trump would grant full pardons to all four men.
是也该给他们发个勋章
And uh, yeah, should give 'em a medal too.
1968年，进行了“极速快递”行动
In 1968, we'd see Operation Speedy Express,
这是1968年12月到1969年5月间，由朱利安·尤厄尔将军指挥的
which was a major U.S. counter-insurgency campaign
陆军第九步兵师在湄公河三角洲进行的一场主要的美军反叛乱行动
carried out by the Army's 9th Infantry Division in the Mekong Delta between December 1968 and May 1969, under General Julian Uwell.
官方说法是，这次任务旨在切断越共的补给线
Officially, the mission aimed to cut Viet Cong supply lines
让他们在三角洲无处藏身
and deny them sanctuary in the Delta,
部署了8000名步兵、火炮、直升机炮艇和数千次空袭
deploying 8,000 infantry, artillery, helicopter gunships, and thousands of airstrikes.
陆军声称击毙了超过10800名敌军
The Army would claim over 10,800 enemy killed in action,
但只缴获了不到750件武器，这个巨大的差距立刻就引起了怀疑
but recovered fewer than 750 weapons, which was a glaring imbalance that raised immediate suspicion.
后来一份监察长的审查估计，死者中可能有多达5000到7000人是平民
A later Inspector General review estimated that as many 5,000 to 7,000 civilians may have been among the dead.
这次行动的后续争议极大
The operation's legacy remains bitterly controversial,
像大卫·哈克沃思上校这样的批评者就描述了指挥官们如何痴迷于杀敌数
as critics such as Colonel David Hackworth would describe how commanders obsessed over body counts
给部队施压以求战果，导致平民在自由开火区被当成目标
and pressured units to produce results, resulting in civilians being targeted in free-fire zones.
尤厄尔本人被指控鼓励一种简单粗暴的作战方式
Uwell himself was accused of encouraging a brute-force approach,
还得了个“三角洲屠夫”的绰号，据说他还引以为豪
earning the nickname The Butcher of the Delta, which he reportedly accepted with pride.
1950年，发生了老根里大屠杀
In 1950, we'd see the Nogeunni Massacre,
这是朝鲜战争开战头一个月里，美国第七骑兵团的部队对韩国难民的一次屠杀
which was a killing of South Korean refugees by U.S. 7th Cavalry Regiment troops during the chaotic first month of the Korean War.
当时朝鲜的进攻迫使美韩军队撤退
As North Korea's invasion drove U.S. and South Korean forces into retreat
有传言说朝鲜渗透者藏在难民中
and rumors spread that North Korean infiltrators were hidden among refugees,
美军指挥部发布了战区范围的指令，要求拦截
American commands issued theater-wide instructions to halt,
并且在多起事件中，向靠近的平民群体开火
and in multiple cases, opened fire on approaching civilian groups.
7月26日，美军将数百名来自秋谷里和任溪里等地的村民
On July 26th, after U.S. troops funneled hundreds of villagers from Chugok-ri and Imgye-ri and elsewhere
从公路上赶到附近的铁轨上
off the road and onto nearby rail tracks,
在接下来的大约60个小时里，这些人遭到了机枪、步枪、迫击炮和火炮的屠杀
these people were massacred by machine gun fire, rifles, mortars, and artillery across roughly 60 hours.
幸存的老兵和目击者描述了探照灯
Eyewitness veterans and survivors described searchlights,
点射和扫射的场景，孩子们喝着被血染红的溪水
potshots, and bursts, children drank from streams reddened with blood,
任何试图逃跑的人都会招来枪火
and attempts to escape drew fire.
2001年美国陆军的一份调查承认，美军在老根里杀害了“数量不详”的平民
A 2001 U.S. Army inquiry acknowledged that U.S. forces killed a, quote, unknown number of civilians at Nogeunni,
但调查把这说成是战争中不幸的副产品
but framed it as a tragic byproduct of war
否认有蓄意杀人的命令，也没有提供道歉或赔偿
and denied deliberate orders to kill, and offered no apologies or compensation.
不过，比尔·克林顿总统表达了深切的遗憾，还资助了一个纪念奖学金计划
However, President Bill Clinton would express deep regret and funded a memorial scholarship proposal.
2005年，发生了哈迪塞大屠杀
In 2005, we see the Haditha Massacre
当时一枚简易爆炸装置炸毁了伊拉克哈迪塞市的一辆海军陆战队悍马车
after an IED tore apart a Marine Humvee in the Iraqi city of Haditha,
炸死了下士米格尔·特拉萨斯，还伤了另外两人
killing Lance Corporal Miguel Terrazas and injuring two others.
紧接着，海军陆战队员就射杀了附近一辆出租车上的五名手无寸铁的男子
In the immediate aftermath, Marines shot five unarmed men from a nearby taxi,
然后接到“占领一所房子”的命令后
and then following an order to take a house,
他们用手榴弹和近距离步枪扫射，冲进了四座相邻的房屋
move through four adjacent homes using grenades and close-range rifle fire,
又杀害了19名平民，男女老少都有，很多人头部和胸部中了数枪
killing 19 more civilians, men, women, and children, many struck multiple times in the head and chest,
这些你都能看到照片，我不建议看，但确实有
all of which you can see photos of. I do not advise, but it's there.
海军陆战队悄悄地向15名受害者的家属支付了高达3万8千美元的赔偿金
The Marine Corps would quietly pay a whopping $38,000 to families of 15 victims.
好耶
Yippee.
2006年12月，八名海军陆战队员被起诉
And eight Marines would be charged in December of 2006.
但最终，只有一个人受到了惩罚
But ultimately, only one person would be punished.
弗兰克·伍特里奇中士，他在2012年对一项玩忽职守的罪名认罪
Sergeant Frank Wuthrich, who pled guilty in 2012 to a single count of negligent derelection of duty.
他被降了级、扣了工资，但一天牢都没坐，干得漂亮
He received a rank reduction and pay cut. Served no jail time. Nice.
2006年，发生了马哈茂迪耶强奸杀人事件
In 2006, we see the Mahmoudia rape killings
发生在3月12日，是美国陆军第502步兵团的士兵在伊拉克战争期间干的
on March 12th that were perpetrated by U.S. Army soldiers from the 502nd Infantry Regiment during the Iraq War,
当时他们离开了尤瑟菲亚附近的一个检查站
when they left a checkpoint near Yusufiyah
在大白天闯进了附近贾纳比一家的住宅，把一家人分开关在不同房间
and entered the nearby home of the Al-Janabi family in daylight and separated its members into rooms.
专员保罗·科尔特斯和詹姆斯·巴克
Specialists Paul E. Cortez and James P. Barker
强奸了14岁的阿比尔·卡西姆·哈姆扎·贾纳比
raped 14-year-old Abir Qasim Hamzal Al-Janabi,
与此同时，一等兵斯蒂芬·格林谋杀了她的母亲、父亲和妹妹
while Private First Class Stephen D. Green murdered her mother, father, and sister,
然后也强奸了阿比尔，并朝她头部开了一枪
and then proceeded to rape Abir and shot her in the head.
这些士兵放火烧了她的尸体
The soldiers set her body on fire
还试图用一把AK-47伪造现场，然后回到基地去“庆祝”
and attempted to stage the scene with an AK-47 before returning to base to, quote, celebrate.
之后的起诉分成了两条线
The prosecutions would follow dual tracks.
因为斯蒂芬·格林在罪行曝光前，就因为精神不稳定被行政开除了
As Stephen D. Green had been administratively discharged for mental instability before the crime surfaced,
所以他是根据《军事域外管辖权法》，在美国联邦法院受审的
he was tried in U.S. federal court under Military Extraterritorial Jurisdiction Act,
他被判犯有强奸罪和四项谋杀罪，被判处终身监禁不得假释
and he would be convicted of rape and four murders and sentenced to life without parole.
不过，他在2014年自杀了
However, he died by suicide in 2014.
科尔特斯在军事法庭上认罪，罪名是强奸、共谋和四项谋杀，被判了100年
Cortez would plead guilty and court-martialed to rape, conspiracy, and four murders and received 100 years.
巴克承认了强奸和谋杀罪，被判了90年
Barker would plead guilty to a rape and murderer and received 90 years.
杰西·斯皮尔曼被判犯有强奸
And Jesse V. Spillman would be convicted of rape,
共谋、非法闯入和四项重罪谋杀罪，被判了110年
conspiracy, housebreaking, and four counts of felony murder and sentenced to 110 years.
另一名没有参与杀戮的士兵被判了27个月监禁、降职并被不光彩地“退役”了
And another soldier who did not participate in the killings received 27 months of the motion and a dishonorable discharge.
1981年，埃尔莫索特大屠杀，这事儿发生在12月11日到12日
In 1981, we'd see the El Mozote massacre that unfolded on December 11th to December 12th,
当时由美国训练的萨尔瓦多阿特拉卡特营
when El Salvador's U.S. trained at Le Cato Battalion
冲进了埃尔莫索特和周围的村庄，处决了超过800名平民
swept into El Mozote and surrounding hamlets and executed more than 800 civilians.
人们遭受审讯、酷刑，最终被枪杀
People were interrogated, tortured, and shot,
妇女和女孩惨遭毒手，连孩童也未能幸免于难
while women and girls wereraped and murdered and children were slaughtered,
整个村子都被烧光了
and the entire village was burned down.
埃尔莫索特本身一直以中立和主要信奉福音派而闻名
Now, El Mozote itself had been known as neutral and largely evangelical,
居民们之所以留下来
and residents had stayed there after
是因为得到了保证说他们在萨尔瓦多内战期间会是安全的
assurances that they would be safe during this Salvadoran civil war.
然而，是啊，这并不是事实
However, yeah, this was not the case.
萨尔瓦多军方和美国官员起初把这些报告斥为游击队的宣传
The Salvadoran military and U.S. officials would dismiss these reports as guerrilla propaganda,
但1992年由联合国支持的尸体发掘证实了大规模平民处决的存在
but U.N.-backed exhumations in 1992 confirmed mass civilian executions.
联合国真相委员会后来得出结论
And the U.N. Truth Commission later concluded that
阿特拉卡特营蓄意并系统性地杀害了埃尔莫索特及附近村庄的非战斗人员
the At-Le Cato deliberately and systematically killed the non-combatant population in El Mozote and nearby hamlets.
华盛顿方面承认他们犯了“错误”
Washington conceded that they made, quote, mistakes,
而在2011年12月，萨尔瓦多政府正式道歉了
and in December 2011, the Salvadoran government formally apologized.
哎哟喂
Aww.
2015年10月3日，在昆都士战役期间
In 2015, on October 3rd, during the Battle of Kunduz,
一架美国空军的AC-130U炮艇机反复轰炸了阿富汗昆都士的一家创伤医院
a U.S. Air Force AC-130 U-gun ship repeatedly bombed a trauma hospital in Kunduz, Afghanistan,
炸死了至少42名医生、员工、病人和看护人员，还有超过30人受伤
killing at least 42 doctors, staff, patients, and caretakers, and injuring more than 30 others.
尽管医院的坐标在几天前就已经和交战各方分享并再次确认过了
Despite the hospital's coordinates being shared and reconfirmed with warring parties days earlier,
空袭还是持续了将近一个小时
the strikes lasted nearly an hour.
就算官员们紧急联系了美国和阿富汗当局，空袭也还在继续
It continued even after officials urgently contacted U.S. and Afghan authorities.
幸存者描述说，病人们在床上被活活烧死，员工们被弹片斩首或肢解
Survivors described patients burning alive in their beds, staff decapitated or dismembered by shrapnel,
还有些人在试图逃离燃烧的院子时，被从空中射杀
and others shot from the air as they tried to escape the flaming compound.
北约、美国军方以及一个阿富汗-美国联合小组的调查结论是
Investigations by NATO, the U.S. military, and a joint Afghan-U.S. group concluded the attack was caused by, quote,
这次袭击是由“可避免的人为错误”造成的，还加上了设备故障和导航失误
avoidable human error, compounded by equipment failures and navigation mistakes,
炮艇机错把医院当成了塔利班的阵地，对着错误的建筑打了211发炮弹
with the gunship firing 211 shells at the wrong building after mistaking it for a Taliban position.
没有任何人面临刑事指控，总统贝拉克·奥巴马发表了正式道歉
No personnel faced criminal charges, and President Barack Obama issued a formal apology.
1830年，“血泪之路”，这是美国政府的强制迁移政策
In 1830, we'd see the Trail of Tears, which was the U.S. government's forced displacement
大约6万名切罗基、穆斯科吉、塞米诺尔、奇克索和乔克托部落的人
of roughly 60,000 people from the Cherokee, Muscogee, Seminole, Chickasaw, and Choctaw nations
被迫从他们东南部的家园，迁往密西西比河以西的所谓“印第安人领地”
from their southeastern homelands to, quote, Indian territory west of the Mississippi
这是在国会通过了1830年的《印第安人迁移法案》之后发生的
after Congress passed the 1830 Indian Removal Act.
没错，我们聊过很多次了，这就是种族灭绝
Yeah, we've talked about this plenty of times. This was a genocide.
1863年还有熊河大屠杀
We'd see the Bear Creek Massacre in 1863,
当时帕特里克·康纳上校手下的大约200名加州志愿兵
when roughly 200 California volunteers under
袭击了爱达荷州一个设防的西北肖肖尼人冬季营地
Colonel Patrick Conner attacked a fortified northwestern Cheshirene winter encampment in Idaho,
估计杀害了250到400名儿童、妇女和男子，有记录描述了
and killing an estimated 250 to 400 children, women, and men, with accounts describing
性暴力、摧毁70个帐篷和储藏物，以及像“猎熊人”这样的首领的死亡
sexual violence, the destruction of 70 lodges and stores, and the deaths of leaders such as Bear Hunter.
这事儿甚至还让帕特里克·康纳升了官
And this even earned Patrick Conner a promotion.
是啊
Yeah.
1864年还有沙溪大屠杀，当时约翰·奇文顿上校的科罗拉多部队
In 1864, we'd also see the Sandy Creek Massacre, when Colonel John M. Chivington's
袭击了一个基本上是和平的夏安-阿拉帕霍村庄
Colorado troops attacked a mostly peaceful Cheyenne Arapaho village
他们当时在美国的安全保证下扎营
camped under U.S. assurances of safety.
士兵们用步枪和榴弹炮开火，杀害了大约150人，大多是妇女和儿童
Soldiers opened fire with rifles and howitzers, killing around 150 people, mostly women and children,
目击者描述了普遍存在的肢解和亵渎尸体的行为
and eyewitnesses described widespread mutilation and desecration of bodies.
虽然后来的调查谴责这次屠杀是“卑鄙下流的行径”
Though later inquiries would condemn the massacre as a foul and dastardly act,
但奇文顿逃脱了惩罚
Chivington escaped punishment.
他离拿勋章就差那么一点点，要是他当时在伤膝河就好了
But he was only so close to a medal, if only he would have been at Wounded Knee.
1890年12月29日
On December 29th, 1890,
当时美国第七骑兵团在松岭印第安人保留地
when the U.S. 7th Calvary surrounded Spotted Elks, Miniconju Lakota,
伤膝河附近包围了斑点麋鹿的米尼康茹拉科塔部落
near Wounded Knee Creek on the Pine Ridge Reservation.
他们被护送到那里，当时定居者对“鬼舞”感到恐慌
After being escorted there, amid settler panic over the ghost dance
背景是土地被掠夺、条约被撕毁、口粮被克扣，野牛也快被赶尽杀绝了
and a grinding backdrop of land seizures, broken treaty rations, and near eradication of the bison,
詹姆斯·福赛思上校领导的这个团，准备解除大约120名拉科塔男子的武装
the regiment under Colonel James W. Forsythe moved to disarm roughly 120 Lakota men
这个营地里总共有大概350人
in a camp of around 350 people.
在紧张的搜查中，一个叫“黑郊狼”的聋人，拒绝交出他的一支步枪
During this tense search, a deaf man, Black Coyote, resisted surrendering one of his rifles,
在随后的挣扎中，他的枪走火了
and in the ensuing struggle, his gun discharged.
士兵们于是开始开火
Soldiers would then proceed to open fire,
不分青红皂白地向几乎所有人扫射
and indiscriminately shot at pretty much everybody.
一个小时内，超过250人死亡
Within an hour, more than 250 people were dead,
包括妇女和儿童
including women and children.
是啊
Yeah.
19枚荣誉勋章因为在伤膝河的行动而颁发
19 Medals of Honor were awarded for actions of Wounded Knee,
31枚是为整个战役发的
31 for the broader campaign.
是啊，哥们
Yeah, man.
我个人认为，把美国的最高军事荣誉颁发给像“伤膝河大屠杀”那样的参与者
I would personally say that handing out America's highest military honor for massacres like Wounded Knee,
而且还不肯承认说“嘿，这事儿或许是错的”
and not recognizing, hey, maybe that was a bad thing,
is more than just rewriting history.
这已经不仅仅是篡改历史了
这简直就是往那些真正赢得这份荣誉的人的坟墓上吐口水
It's literally spitting on the graves of those who actually earned it.
荣誉勋章本应代表勇气、牺牲，和对人类生命不可动摇的捍卫
The Medal of Honor is supposed to represent courage, sacrifice, and an unshakable defense of human life,
即使是面对死亡，也要捍卫生命
even in the face of death.
把它颁给犯下战争罪行的人
And giving it to people who commit war crimes
完全稀释了这个名号的价值
completely dilutes the name,
也侮辱了那些行动体现了这些价值观的真正英雄
and disrespects the actual heroes whose actions embody these values.
德斯蒙德·多斯，二战中的一位基督复临安息日会医疗兵，他赤手空拳上战场
Desmond Doss, a Seventh-day Adventist medic in World War II, who literally went into battle with his bare hands,
在冲绳的炮火下仍然救了75个人
and still saves 75 men under fire in Okinawa.
弗农·贝克，最早因为他在二战意大利的行动获得荣誉勋章的黑人士兵之一
Vernon J. Baker, one of the first black soldiers to receive the Medal of Honor for his actions in Italy during World War II.
井上建，一位来自夏威夷的日裔美国人
Daniel Inouye, a Japanese-American  from Hawaii,
他在意大利冲击纳粹防线时失去了一条手臂
who lost an arm storming Nazi defenses in Italy,
后来当了几十年的美国参议员
went on to serve as a U.S. Senator for decades.
还有何塞·洛佩斯，一位在突出部战役中的墨西哥裔机枪手
Or Jose M. Lopez, a Mexican-American machine gunner in the Battle of the Bulge,
也就是阿登战役
他几乎单枪匹马地抵挡住了德军，保护了他的部队
who held off German forces almost single-handedly protecting his unit.
小米切尔·雷德克劳德，一位霍-琼克族的原住民
Mitchell Red Cloud Jr., a ho-chunk Native American
在朝鲜战争中即使身负重伤也继续向中国军队开火
who continued firing on Chinese troops in Korea, even after being mortally wounded,
什么树开什么花，什么阶级说什么话
为他的连队重整赢得了时间
buying time for his company to regroup.
这些人才是赢得荣誉勋章的人
These are the kinds of people who earned the Medal of Honor.
那些将自己置于难以想象的危险中的男女，不是为了征服
Men and women who place themselves in unimaginable danger, not for conquest,
不是为了残忍，而是为了真正地拯救生命和保护他人
not for cruelty, but to actually save lives and protect others.
我不知道，哥们儿
Like, I don't know.
可能是我脑子瓦特了，可能是我疯了
Maybe I'm tripping. Maybe I'm tripping.
我真的不知道
I don't know, guys.
我花了一整晚把这个录完的，我真的很累，我要上床了
I record this all in one night. I'm really tired. I'm gonna go back to bed.
但是，是啊，这肯定不是全部，拜托了，在下面的评论里，真的
But, yeah. Of course, this is, like, not everything. And please, in the comments below, please,
求求你们了，把其他的事儿也列出来，因为我肯定漏了很多
please, I'm begging you to list other things out. Because, of course, I miss, there's, you know,
你知道的，肯定还有更多
you know there's plenty more.
但是，我的天啊，我不知道
But, oh my god. I don't know.
我心态崩了哥们儿，我真的心态崩了
I'm frustrated, man. I'm frustrated,
而且我也累了。我觉得我要回去睡觉了
and I'm tired. And I think I'm gonna go to bed.
但是，感谢收看，希望你们一切都好
But, thank you for watching. And I hope you're doing well.
还有，爱你哦，兄弟
And, yeah, I love you, bro.